<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bakoko_desc">
        \t\tBakoko fish, also known as Sea Bream, is a common saltwater species found in the Philippines, prized for its delicate flavor and versatility in cooking.
        \n\nIt is a popular choice in Filipino cuisine and often featured in dishes such as sinigang na isda (fish sour soup) and paksiw na isda (fish braised in vinegar).
        \n\nBakoko fish are known for their silvery scales, deep bodies, and distinctive forked tails.
        \n\nThey inhabit coastal waters and coral reefs, feeding on small fish, crustaceans, and mollusks.
        \n\nBakoko are known for their high nutritional value, being rich sources of protein, omega-3 fatty acids, vitamins, and minerals, contributing to a healthy diet when consumed regularly.

    </string>
    <string name="banak_desc">
        \t\tBanak, also known as Sea Mullet, are commonly found in brackish or coastal waters throughout the Philippines.
        \n\nIt has elongated bodies and silvery scales, typically growing to a moderate size ranging from 20 to 50 centimeters in length.
        \n\nBanak are herbivorous fish, feeding primarily on algae, plankton, and detritus, contributing to coastal ecosystem balance.
        \n\nPrized for its firm texture and mild flavor, Banak is versatile in Filipino cuisine and used in dishes like sinigang, paksiw, and kinilaw.
        \n\nDue to its abundance and affordability, Banak is a popular choice among Filipino households and local markets.

    </string>
    <string name="bangus_desc">
        \t\tBangus, also known as Milkfish, is the national fish of the Philippines, deeply rooted in Filipino culture and cuisine.
        \n\nBangus farming is a vital industry in the Philippines, supporting livelihoods and contributing to both domestic consumption and export.
        \n\nBangus is cultivated through various methods, including freshwater ponds, brackish water areas, and sea cages.
        \n\nBangus is a versatile ingredient in Filipino cuisine, prepared in numerous ways such as grilling, frying, or stewing.
        \n\nBangus is rich in protein, vitamins, and omega-3 fatty acids, offering nutritional benefits for consumers.

    </string>
    <string name="carp_desc">
        \t\tCarp, is a freshwater species widely found in the Philippines, recognized for its hardiness and adaptability to various aquatic environments.
        \n\nIt is characterized by its robust body, typically olive-green or bronze in color, with scales along its sides and a pair of barbels near its mouth.
        \n\Carp fish is omnivorous, feeding on a diet of plants, insects, crustaceans, and small fish, contributing to its role in ecosystem balance and nutrient cycling.
        \n\nThis fish species is commonly cultivated in ponds, lakes, and rivers for aquaculture purposes due to its rapid growth rate and high reproductive capacity.
        \n\nCarp fish is valued for its tender flesh and mild flavor, making it suitable for various cooking methods such as frying, grilling, baking, or steaming.
        \n\nWhen purchasing carp fish from local markets, consumers should ensure its freshness by checking for clear eyes, firm flesh, and a mild odor, and should store it properly to maintain its quality for cooking.

    </string>
    <string name="dalag_desc">
        \t\tDalag, also known as Mudfish, is a freshwater species native to the Philippines, often found in rivers, lakes, and swamps.
        \n\nIt is characterized by its elongated body, olive-brown coloration, and distinctive ability to breathe air and travel short distances over land.
        \n\nDalag fish is omnivorous, feeding on a diet of small fish, insects, crustaceans, and vegetation, contributing to its adaptability to various aquatic environments.
        \n\nKnown for its firm texture and flavorful flesh, dalag fish is a popular ingredient in Filipino cuisine and is used in dishes such as sinigang, paksiw, and adobo.
        \n\nWhile dalag fish is readily available in local markets, consumers should ensure its freshness by checking for clear eyes, firm flesh, and a mild odor, and should store it properly to maintain its quality for cooking.

    </string>
    <string name="pangasius_desc">
        \t\tPangasius fish, also known as Cream Dory, is characterized by its mild flavor, white flesh, and relatively low cost, making it a popular choice in the local market and restaurant industry.
        \n\nPangasius is known for its rapid growth rate and high yield in aquaculture settings, contributing to its affordability and availability in the Philippines.
        \n\nPangasius is rich in protein, low in fat, and a good source of essential nutrients like vitamins D and B12, making it a nutritious option for consumers.
        \n\nPangasius is versatile in cooking and can be prepared in various ways such as grilling, frying, baking, or steaming, offering flexibility in culinary applications.
        \n\nWhen purchasing Pangasius, consumers should ensure its freshness and quality by checking for clear, bright eyes, firm flesh, and a mild odor, and should store it properly to maintain its freshness and safety for consumption.

    </string>
    <string name="salay_salay_desc">
       \t\tSalay-salay fish, also known as horse mackerel, is a common saltwater species found in the Philippines, characterized by its elongated body and silvery coloration.
        \n\nIt is known for its firm, flavorful flesh and is often prized for its culinary versatility, suitable for grilling, frying, baking, or steaming.
        \n\nSalay-salay fish is rich in omega-3 fatty acids, protein, and essential nutrients, making it a nutritious choice for consumers.
        \n\nThis fish species is commonly found in coastal waters and feeds on small fish, crustaceans, and plankton, contributing to its robust flavor profile.
        \n\nWhen selecting salay-salay fish from local markets, consumers should ensure freshness by checking for clear eyes, firm flesh, and a mild sea scent, and should store it properly to maintain its quality for cooking.

    </string>
    <string name="sardine_desc">
        \t\tSardine, is a small, oily fish species found in abundance in Philippine waters, particularly along coastal areas and near shorelines.
        \n\nIt is characterized by its silver-colored body, streamlined shape, and distinctive flavor, which is slightly sweet and briny.
        \n\nSardines are known for their high omega-3 fatty acid content, making them a nutritious choice that supports heart health and brain function.
        \n\nThis fish species is commonly found in large schools, making them easy to catch and a significant part of local fisheries in the Philippines.
        \n\nSardines are often consumed fresh, canned, or preserved in various ways, such as pickling or smoking, and are a staple ingredient in Filipino dishes like pinangat, ginataan, and kilawin.
        \n\nWhen purchasing sardines from local markets, consumers should look for bright, clear eyes, shiny scales, and firm flesh, and should store them properly to maintain their freshness and flavor.

    </string>
    <string name="tilapia_desc">
        \t\tTilapia fish is one of the most widely cultured and consumed freshwater fish species in the Philippines, valued for its mild taste and versatile culinary applications.
        \n\nIt is commonly raised in fishponds, lakes, and freshwater reservoirs throughout the country due to its adaptability to various environmental conditions.
        \n\nTilapia is known for its fast growth rate, high reproductive capacity, and resilience to disease, making it an economically important aquaculture species.
        \n\nIn Filipino cuisine, tilapia is prepared in various ways such as grilled, fried, steamed, or used in soups and stews like sinigang and nilaga.
        \n\nTilapia is a nutritious source of protein, low in fat, and rich in essential nutrients like vitamins D and B12, making it a popular choice for health-conscious consumers.

    </string>
</resources>